## **GAN SAU YANG**

Address: BLK495A, Tampines street 43, 520495

**Mobile:** +6587561236

**WhatsApp:** +60162786399

Email: sauyang1009@gmail.com

**Portfolio:** https://sauyang.github.io/portfolio/

Expected Salary: SGD 4300 Singapore Permanent Resident



#### **Objective**

Android developer with 3 years+ experience in mobile banking app, I am constantly learning and updating the latest changes. I have been refining my programming skill with banking app projects, learning from experts, online resources and self-learning (Pluralsight).

I am looking for an opportunity where I can put those abilities to work for a mission I am passionate about. My current role is Android developer, my daily responsibilities include: developing new app feature and module, testing and improving existing banking app, integrating third-party libraries & components, producing clean and efficient code base on specifications.

Relevant job skills: capable of developing Android native app and beginner level in iOS. Successfully designed and implemented many new modules and features for Hong Leong Connect (Malaysia), Hong Leong Connect (Vietnam) and DBS IDEAL mobile app. I have passion for my job because it is challenging and tedious. For example, there are many Android OS versions behave differently, developer needs to optimum performance for many different Android OS.

#### **Skills**

- Android SDK
- Version Control System using Subversion, Git Bitbucket
- Kotlin & Java programming

- Webservice REST, SOAP XML & JSON format
- Google Play Service, Map, Firebase FCM, Notification and Crashlytics
- Android App pen-test using Jenkins
- Microsoft Azure hosting Web-app (ASP.NET)

#### **Education**

#### ASIA PACIFIC UNIVERSITY - BSc (Hons) in Information Technology

May 2011 - Dec 2015

- I worked as a computer lab technical assistant. Experience on configuring, monitoring, upgrading and maintaining systems hardware, software and related infrastructure.
- Networking knowledge (Mobile & Wireless Technology) such as DHCP, routing, switching and VOIP.
- Android Java programming knowledge, Programming C & C++, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office, Cloud hosting Web-App using Microsoft Azure and Microsoft ASP.Net.

# Working **Experience**

## Mobile Android developer - Silverlake Mobility Ecosystem SDN BHD

May 2016 – Jan 2019

- I worked on a small Agile team in a startup environment to build mobile app for demanding clients.
- Develop digital banking modules for consumer bank Hong Leong Connect (Malaysia) & Hong Leong Connect Vietnam such as Online transfer, Account Overview, Credit Card Service and so on.
- UI/UX design using Android Native layout, ensure layout & code are easily readable and maintable such as implementing layout component, MVC project pattern.

- Integrating web-services request & response from server-side and got the experience of using REST service API call, handling web-service data response in SOAP XML and JSON format
- Technical skills, Android Native SDK skills such as permission, camera and Android OS behavior. Google Play services, Firebase Crashlytics, Google Map (GPS enabled) using it to check nearby bank branches, location is determined by GPS signals. Solving Android OS compatibility issues, such as replacing deprecated SDK calling methods.

### Mobile Android developer - Pactera Singapore PTE LTD

Feb 2019 – April 2020

- Project: DBS IDEAL mobile banking app for business. Developing business transaction modules such as fund transfer module, scan & pay integration using third-party QR and Google FCM notification.
- Payee Creation & Management module, supporting overseas fund transfer to many foreign banks. User can easily select the created payee to proceed the type of fund transfer. Message from DBS module, allow user to choose image, PDF and various extension file with text message, send it as a message for inquiry, report an issue or feedback. Manage Alerts module, allowing user to check transaction alert such as high/low balance, user will receive notification when the account balance is reaching the high/low balance, there are many types of alerts user can choose to activate.
- Third party library integration, V-KEY software token for DBS IDEAL digital token. Ensures digital token is working for mobile devices (needed for web login/transaction approval), replacing traditional hardware token OTP & SMS OTP.

- Adding Android fingerprint feature for quick login and transaction approval, extra encryption is added with cipher and SecretKey store in AndroidKeystore to avoid fingerprint bypass.

**Hobby** 

Running, Hiking, Workout & Yoga. I agree healthy lifestyle is important, I always maintain exercising at least two days per week.

\*I am not convenient to answer phone call during working hours, please contact me via WhatsApp: +60162786399 or Email: <a href="mailto:sauyang1009@gmail.com">sauyang1009@gmail.com</a>
I will reply as soon as possible, thanks.